<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>face0xff's den</title><link>/</link><description>Recent content on face0xff's den</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>CVE-2023-51364, CVE-2023-51365 in QNAP QTS — Remote Code Execution</title><link>/cves/cve-2023-51364-51365-qnap-qts-rce/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/cves/cve-2023-51364-51365-qnap-qts-rce/</guid><description>
A chain of vulnerabilities in QNAP NAS devices allowed a local or remote attacker to reliably gain code execution with root privilege.</description></item><item><title>CVE-2021-38666 in Windows — Remote Code Execution in the RDP client</title><link>/cves/cve-2021-38666-microsoft-rdp-client-rce/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/cves/cve-2021-38666-microsoft-rdp-client-rce/</guid><description>
In Microsoft Remote Desktop, a malicious RDP server could remotely execute code in a client through the RDPDR extension (enabled by default).</description></item><item><title>CVE-2021-38665 in Windows — Remote Heap Leak in the RDP client</title><link>/cves/cve-2021-38665-microsoft-rdp-client-heap-leak/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/cves/cve-2021-38665-microsoft-rdp-client-heap-leak/</guid><description>
In Microsoft Remote Desktop, a malicious RDP server could remotely leak heap memory from a client through the RDPDR extension (enabled by default).</description></item><item><title>CVE-2021-37595 in FreeRDP — Remote Arbitrary File Read</title><link>/cves/cve-2021-37595-freerdp-remote-arbitrary-file-read/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/cves/cve-2021-37595-freerdp-remote-arbitrary-file-read/</guid><description>
In FreeRDP &lt; 2.4.0 (Windows), a malicious RDP server can remotely read arbitrary files from a client's system through the clipboard extension (enabled by default).</description></item><item><title>CVE-2021-37594 in FreeRDP — Remote Memory Leak</title><link>/cves/cve-2021-37594-freerdp-remote-memory-leak/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/cves/cve-2021-37594-freerdp-remote-memory-leak/</guid><description>
In FreeRDP &lt; 2.4.0 (Windows), a malicious RDP server can remotely leak memory from a client's system through the clipboard extension (enabled by default).</description></item><item><title>Patching Steam binaries</title><link>/posts/patching-steam-binaries/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/patching-steam-binaries/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Patching Steam executable files can prove useful for diverse purposes, one of those being vulnerability research in the Steam client. This short post will explain how you can circumvent a few obstacles to achieve that, before presenting an applied example.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>European Cyber Week CTF Quals 2021 — Pipe Dream (Writeup)</title><link>/posts/ecw-ctf-2021-pipe-dream-writeup/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/ecw-ctf-2021-pipe-dream-writeup/</guid><description>
&lt;p>From October 8th to October 24th took place the &lt;strong>online qualification round for the European Cyber Week CTF Finals&lt;/strong>, that are held every year in Rennes, France.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I had the opportunity to &lt;strong>create a challenge&lt;/strong> for this event as part of my internship at Thalium. This was the first time I actually publish a challenge and I hope those who gave it a try enjoyed it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>About me</title><link>/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/about/</guid><description>
I am a security analyst and reverse engineer from France.
I love computer science, security and challenges. I am especially drawn to fields such as offensive security, reverse engineering, binary exploitation and cryptography. I love learning and sharing my knowledge.
Previously, I have played CTFs with SHRECS, a team that I created with fellow students of my university. During that time, we helped promoting the CTF culture in CentraleSupélec, and won multiple competitions such as Imperial CTF, HackDay, THCon CTF and Orange CTF.</description></item><item><title>Challenges</title><link>/challenges/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/challenges/</guid><description>
As much as I love solving CTF challenges, I also greatly enjoy designing my own puzzles. This page indexes some challenges I have created in the past for various occasions (not an exhaustive list).
SSTIC 2024: The Green Shard Brawl #pwn #linux #heap
A binary exploitation problem created for the renowned, annual SSTIC challenge. It consists of a Linux client for a multi-player SDL game written in C, and a Python server that implements a custom protocol.</description></item><item><title>Research</title><link>/research/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/research/</guid><description>
Talks Bug hunting in Steam: a journey into the Remote Play protocol (SSTIC 2023) (paper) Fuzzing Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s RDP Client using Virtual Channels (SSTIC 2022) (paper) CVEs CVE-2023-51364, CVE-2023-51365 in QNAP QTS — Remote Code Execution CVE-2021-38666 in Windows — Remote Code Execution in the RDP client CVE-2021-38665 in Windows — Remote Heap Leak in the RDP client CVE-2021-37595 in FreeRDP — Remote Arbitrary File Read CVE-2021-37594 in FreeRDP — Remote Memory Leak Other Remote Code Execution in Steam Remote Play</description></item></channel></rss>